Dustin Holden

Phone: (612) 568-3649

Address: Greater Atlanta Area

Website: http://lovemhz.com

http://github.com/lovemhz

Fmail: dustin@devholden.com Experienced developer with over 10 years of experience planning, developing, and implementing both desktop and web-based application solutions, with excellent client and project management skills. Action-oriented with strong ability to communicate effectively with technology, executive, and business audiences. Driven to deliver quality solutions.

EXPERIENCE

APRIL 2012 TO PRESENT **DEVHOLDEN LLC**

Owner/Interactive Media Developer

Started DEVHOLDEN LLC in mid-2012 as a interactive development company with the goal of providing solutions for small to medium sized businesses.

DEVHOLDEN currently utilizes object oriented PHP using the MVC model based framework CakePHP 3 or a MEAN(MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, and Node JS) stack based solution using the Mean.js or Meteor framework depending on requirements of the project. Front end development consists of AngularJS, Bower, Grunt, and SCSS. Our platform of choice for most clients is Amazon Web Services with full service integration of load balancing, CDN, push notifications, emails, SMS, etc.

Worked with small business to develop cost effective software and website solutions as senior developer and project manager.

Cabins For You MARCH 2015 - DEC 2015

Senior Web Application Developer

Worked as Senior Web Application Developer for Cabins For You developing internal property, guest, and reservation management software.

Software stack was developed around Amazon Web Services using CakePHP 3 as the MVC framework and a custom single page application wrapper using AngularJS. Middleware was written in a mix of Java for API integration and Node JS for front end/back end subscription based model/view notifications.

- Securely managed multi-tenant cloud based application.
- Developed SPA framework using AngularJS with tight integration of Websockets through the CakePHP 3 framework and Node JS.
- Integrated internal phone system into web platform.
- Leveraged Amazon Simple Notification Service between the Node JS model/view subscription model for real time notifications to users on both desktop and mobile devices.
- Project was organized in a Agile Scrum workflow.
- Worked directly with departments to establish direction of the software early on.
- Managed server infrastructure, including early testing of PHP7 via HHVM and Nginx HTTP/2.0 support for persistent connections.

VapePCB DEC 2014 - Nov 2015

Owner

Started VapePCB in late December 2014 after seeing the need for a safer unregulated vape device in the market.

VapePCB was a hardware product company developing electronic vaping devices. Product design was done in AutoCad and PCB layout and routing was carried out in KiCad.

- Designed and developed a safer electronic vape device.
- Developed partnerships with component distributors.
- Managed sales of product both online and with retail locations throughout the Greater Atlanta Area.
- Organized promotional events with local businesses and companies.

PopUp Domination

DEC 2013 - DEC 2014

Senior Software Developer

Worked as Senior Web Application Developer for PopUp Domination a Wordpress plugin of the same name. Extensive work was done building and maintaining a lead generating plugin actively used by over 50,000 websites.

PopUp Domination was developed on the AWS, Amazon Web Services, platform using object oriented PHP and MVC design patterns. Marketing pages and plugin themes were developed using technologies such as SCSS/Sass, Grunt, Compass, etc.

- Managed software with an active install base of over 50,000 websites.
- Integrating an automatic plugin update system built on top of the native WordPress update system.
- Strict testing procedures for releases were developed for using unit testing and cross-browser testing via Browserstack.
- Designed and developed responsive lead generating templates for both desktop and mobile.
- · Wrote tools to automatically fix CSS conflicts.
- Integrated multiple mailing list providers through API services. Such as AWeber, Constant Contact, and MailChimp.
- Developed license DRM based on multiple license tiers.

SplashMenu May 2012 - Nov 2013

Owner/Lead Developer

SplashMenu was developed by myself through a partnership with RankAboveOthers whom provided marketing resources and financial support. SplashMenu is a web platform based point of sales application. It easily allows restaurants to integrate a complete online shopping experience for customers to order food from their favorite restaurants.

SplashMenu was written in object oriented PHP using the MVC model based framework CakePHP 2. Front end development consisted of using jQuery, SASS, and Bootstrap for rapid development.

- Supporting multiple payment gateway systems through an expandable system. Such as 2Checkout, Authorize.net, PayPal, and SecurePay.
- Securely managed multi-tenant cloud based application.
- Allow customers to target development branches, while migrating data automatically between them. This allowed users to test out beta branches or stay on minor release branches for compatibility reasons.
- Developed a full client SDK, via a REST API, including examples, themes, and documentation. A key part of the SDK
 was providing a universal layer between different API target branches.
- Advanced caching mechanism for reducing heavy load spikes on clients' sites.
- Development of POS hardware based around existing commodity x86 hardware.
- Porting the Android Operating System to existing x86 based POS registers.
- Reverse engineering of x86 based POS registers.
- · Writing Linux drivers of x86 POS hardware.

WorkforceHQ April 2011 - April 2012

CTO

Worked for WorkforceHQ as CTO and Lead Developer. Primarily worked on Magento based eCommerce websites. Also developed a mobile friendly HTML5 based virtual room designer.

WorkforceHQ utilized object oriented PHP using the MVC model based frameworks CakePHP 2 and Zend for many of our projects. Front end development consisted of using jQuery, SASS, 960gs, and Bootstrap.

- Extensively worked with the Magento eCommerce platform developing online shopping sites.
- Developed Magento extensions.
- Managed sites with large SKUs, 10,000 plus.
- Engaged with clients and UI designers to identify brand design and site functionality.

Rank Above Others

MAY 2009 – FEB 2011

Web Application Developer

Worked for Rank Above Others as Lead Web Developer. Primarily worked on developing commercial Wordpress plugins and SEO analytical tools.

- Developed multiple commercial Wordpress plugins, such as WordPress Shop Builder.
- Developed SEO analytic software for generating detailed reports on websites about their Google SEO ranking, along
 with helpful information on how to improve their site's ranking.

SKILLS

Web Development

General Experience

HTML	10 Years+
CSS	10 Years+
Javascript	10 Years+

PHP Stack Technology

Primary development in PHP5, and PHP7 for projects that both support and benefit from strong type casting. Over the last two years the primary PHP framework I've chosen has migrated from CakePHP to Laravel as it has matured into the tried and tested framework that it is today.

Framework Experience

WordPress	8 Years+
Magento	5 Years+
Laravel	2 Years+
CakePHP	4 Years+
Zend	8 Years+

Javascript Stack Technology

Full stack Javascript is fairly new and in some aspects still considered experimental. Over the past two years I've had the opportunity to work on various full stack Javascript based projects.

Framework and Library Experience

AngularJS	2 Years+
Node JS	1 Years+
ReactJS	1 Years+
MongoDB	2 Years+
Meteor	1 Years+

JavaScript

Experience in Javascript ranges from common jQuery development to fully custom SAP framework development, pre-AngularJS. Hands on experience developing clean, efficient, and unit tested ECMAScript 5 and 6.

Software Development

C++, Embedded C, Python, Game Development, Reverse Engineering, iOS development, Android Development

Misc.

Version Control - GIT	5 Years+
Unit Testing	5 Years+

EDUCATION

Ashworth College Computer Information Management - Undergraduate Certificate

2012 - 2013

PUBLICATIONS

DIY Wifi Enabled Fish Tank

MARCH 19, 2016

http://tinyurl.com/j5uefjn

Weekend project involing turning a simple fish tank into an internet connected device.

Reverse Engineering a Bluetooth Enabled Battery Charger

JANUARY 29, 2016

http://tinyurl.com/zv59dre

Through the never ending stream of "connected" devices on the market we have yet another. Today, I look at and tear into the workings of Efest's latest product, the Efest LUC BLU6 OLED Intelligent Charger.